Guide to the Caldwell B. Esselstyn Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Despite chronic illness (he developed cancer in 1970) Esselstyn continued working, and following his retirement he served, until 1974, as a part-time consultant with the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Health Maintenance Organization Service.
Esselstyn died in Claverack, Columbia County, New York on March 11, 1975.
Health maintenance organizations; Medical care; Medicare; Older people -- Medical care; Public health; Labor unions -- Health facilities; New York (State) -- Rural conditions; United States -- Politics and government -- 1961-1963; Health services administrators; Physicians; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Arnstein, Margaret G.; Baehr, George, 1887-1978; Baumgartner, Leona, 1902-1991; Esselstyn, Caldwell B., 1902-1975; Falk, I. S. (Isidore Sydney), 1899-1984; Gimbel, Elinor; Gold, Milton J.; Hilles, Charles Dewey, 1867-1949; Hiscock, Ira V. (Ira Vaughan), 1892-; Kerr, Lorin E., 1909-; Kirkland, Joseph Lane, 1922-; Kubie, Lawrence S. (Lawrence Schlesinger), 1896-1973; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970; Ribicoff, Abraham, 1910-1998; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Snoke, Albert W. (Albert Waldo), 1907-; Spock, Benjamin, 1903-1998; Voorhis, Jerry, 1901-1984; Woodcock, Leonard, 1911-2001; Wynn, Edward, 1886-; Wynn, Keenan, 1916-1986; New York (State). Metropolitan Regional Medical Program; Public Health Council (N.Y.); New York State Emergency Medical Services Council; United States. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare; United States. Office of Health Maintenance Organizations; American Federation of Labor; American Public Health Association; Community Health Association (Boston, Mass.); Group Health Association of America; Health Insurance Council; Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, Inc; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; Kaiser Foundation Research Institute (Richmond, Calif.); Physicians Committee for Health Care for the Aged Through Social Security; Public Affairs Committee; Rip Van Winkle Foundation; United Mine Workers of America; Yale University. Health Services; Yale University. Department of Public Health
- Correspondence, 1945-1975; Series I; 9' (21 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  CORRESPONDENCE is organized in three sections: Correspondence, 1945-1964, Correspondence & Subject Files, 1964-1975, and Personal Correspondence. Each section is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1945-1964
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Theodore, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Abrams, Herbert K., 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ackerman, Laurence J., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Akron Clinic, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Albany Medical College of Union University, 1948-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Arbitration Association (Box 1, Folder 5)
      General
      See: box 18, folder 437
      General note
      See: box 15, folder 374
    - American Association of Medical Clinics, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6-10)
    - American Association of Medical Clinics, Retirement Fund, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Association of Medical Clinics, Retirement Fund, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - American Association of Retired People, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - American Board of Abdominal Surgery, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - American Cancer Society (Box 2, Folder 14)
      See: box 32, folder 176
    - American Cancer Society, New York State Division, 1959-1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - American College of Surgeons, 1949-1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      See also: box 32, folder 176
    - American Council for the Improvement of Medical Care, Organizing Committee, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      See also: box 6, folder 151
      See also: box 10, folder 249-258
      See also: box 13, folder 306
      See also: box 15, folder 376
      See also: box 19, folder 456
      See also: box 2, folder 31
      See also: box 4, folder 80
      See also: box 6, folder 132
    - American Federation of Medical Centers, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - American Geriatrics Society, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - American Medical Association, 1951-1964 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      See also: box 84, folders 331-364
    - American Medical Association, "Guide to Physician Relationships with Medical Care Plans", 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - American Optometric Association, Inc., Seminar on Social Health Care, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      See also: box 55, folders 62-63
    - American Surgical Association, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Appalachian Regional Hospitals, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      See: box 56, folders 64-69
    - Arneill, James R., 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Arnstein (Elizabeth R.) Fund, 1949-1964 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      See also: box 2, folder 32
    - Arnstein, Margaret (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Associated Medical Schools of Greater New York (Box 2, Folder 26)
      See: box 42, folders 311-374
    - Association of Teachers of Preventive Medicine, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Austin, Edward B., 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Axelrod, Solomon J., 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - B (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Baehr, George (Box 2, Folder 30)
      See: box 16, folder 393
      See: box 19, folder 458
      See: box 44, folder 340
      See: box 78, folders 267-305
      See: box 84, folders 331-364
      See: box 1, folder 9
    - Ball, Robert (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Bamberger, Lisbeth, 1957-1964 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Bannon, Kenneth (Box 2, Folder 31)
      See: box 41, folder 297
    - Barach, Alvan L., 1946-1960 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Bard College, 1955-1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Barr, David P., 1949-1951, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Bartlett, Marshall K., 1948-1962 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Bassett (Mary Imogene) Hospital (Box 3, Folder 35)
      See: box 3, folder 41
    - Baumgartner, Leona (Box 3, Folder 35)
      See box 87, folders 365-370
    - Berger, Edward J., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Berghold, William F., 1951-1957 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Berry, Frank B., 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Bixby, Burdell R., 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Blair, Edwin Foster, 1946-1961 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      See also: box 10, folder 237
      See also: box 81, folder 311
    - Blair, Paxton, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      See: box 24, folder 51
    - Blue Cross-Blue Shield (Box 3, Folder 40)
      See: box 39, folders 274-310
    - Blue Cross of Michigan (Box 3, Folder 40)
      See: box 15, folder 379
      See: box 14, folder 366
    - Bordley, James, III, 1948-1960 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Boys' Club of New York, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Brand, Morris, 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      See also: box 10, folder 255
    - Breslow, Lester, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Brewster, Agnes W., 1957-1964 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Brightman, I. Jay, 1957-1961 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Brindle, James, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      See also: box 1, folder 11
      See also: box 41, folder 294
    - Brown, Howard J., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Brown, Norton Sager, 1946-1959 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      See also: box 6, folder 160
    - C (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Campbell, James A. (Box 3, Folder 50)
      See: box 1, folder 5
    - Canada, Department of National Health and Welfare, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Carlino, Joseph F., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Carroll, Terence E. (Box 3, Folder 52)
      See: box 16, folder 391
      See: box 6, folder 157
    - Carter, Richard, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Case, James H., Jr. (Box 3, Folder 52)
      See box 4, folder 87
      See box 2, folder 32
    - Caughey, John L., Jr., 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Century Association, 1956-1964 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Chatham Courier Co., 1955-1963 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Citizen's Crusade Against Poverty, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Clark, Bliss, 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Clark, Dean A., 1948-1951 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      See also: box 47, folder 371
      See also: box 88, folder 3
    - Clark, Henry T., Jr., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      See also: box 46, folder 365
    - Clarke, Dana C., 1947, 1949, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Cleveland Clinic (Box 3, Folder 59)
      See: box 4, folder 79
    - Clinic Managers Association, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Cohen, Wilbur J., 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Cole, Lewis Gregory, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Columbia County Community College Project, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Columbia County Conference on Youth, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Columbia County Department of Health, 1956-1964 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Columbia County Medical Society (Box 3, Folder 65)
      See: box 15, folder 380
      See: box 34, folder 206
      See: box 81, folder 311
      See: box 88, folder 3
      See: box 5, folder 111
    - Columbia County Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1955-1962 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, 1952-1958 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Columbia University School of Public Health and Administration, 1950, 1958-1964 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Columbia University Teachers College, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Committee for Medical Development, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Community Health Foundation, Cleveland, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Connecticut General Life Insurance Co., 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 72-73)
    - Cooperative League of the U.S.A. (Box 4, Folder 72-73)
      See: box 20, folder 468
    - Council of Social Agencies of Rochester and Monroe County, Inc., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Council to Improve Medical Care, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Count, Jerome, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Cowles, Gardiner, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Cox, Gordon W., 1948-1956 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Crane, A. Reynolds, 1949-1956 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Crile, George, Jr., 1955-1964 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Cruikshank, Nelson H., 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Cutting, Cecil (Box 4, Folder 80)
      See: box 14, folder 349
    - D (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Davis, Michael M., 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      See also: box 54, folder 51
      See also: box 63, folder 146
      See also: box 54, folder 48
    - Dearing, W. Palmer (Box 4, Folder 82)
      See: box 57, folders 79-87
    - Democratic National Committee, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Draper, Warren F., 1955, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - E (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Edelman, John (Box 4, Folder 85)
      See: box 87, folder 361
    - Elling, Roy H., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Empire State Health Council, Inc., 1957-1960, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - English-Speaking Union of the United States, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Erickson, Robert (Box 4, Folder 87)
      See: box 40, folder 288
      See: box 14, folders 349-351
    - F (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Falk, Isidore S., 1956-1964 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      See also: box 1, folder 9
    - Falk, Leslie A., 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 90)
      See also: box 18, folder 448
    - Farrell, J. Cottrell, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Feldman, Louis (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Ficke, Gladys, 1948-1951, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Fisher, A. Murray, 1948-1959 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Fiske, Robert B., 1955-1961 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Flaherty, John Preston, 1948-1960 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Fleming, Scott (Box 4, Folder 94)
      See: box 14, folders 350-351
    - Frantz, Virginia Kneeland, 1949-1960 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Freeman, Victor J., 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Frost, Benson R., 1948-1963 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - G (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Gehrig, Eleanor (Mrs. Lou), 1948-1961 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Gerontological Society, Inc., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Gimbel, Elinor, 1949, 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Gimbel, Nicholas S., 1948-1959 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Glaser, Robert J., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Glasser, Melvin (Box 5, Folder 101)
      See: box 78, folder 273
      See: box 18, folders 442-443
    - Gold, Milton (Box 5, Folder 101)
      See: box 23, folder 40
    - Goldmann, Franz, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Good Housekeeping, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Gordon, Kermit (Box 5, Folder 102)
      See: box 68, folder 196
    - Gorham, L. Whittington, 1946-1964 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Graham, George M., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Greenough, James, 1948, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Group Health Association of America (Box 5, Folder 104)
      See: box 41, folder 295
    - Group Health (St. Paul, Minnesota), 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Group Health Cooperative of Puget Sound, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Group Health Council of Greater New Haven, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Group Health Federation of America (Box 5, Folder 106)
      See: box 5, folder 105
    - Group Health Insurance, Inc. (New York City), 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Gundersen, Sven, M., 1952-1964 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - H (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Haight, Eric (Box 5, Folder 108)
      See: box 12, folder 281
      See: box 20, folder 475-476
    - Halsted, James A., 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Hanlon, John (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Harvard University School of Medicine, 1952-1964 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Health Information Foundation, 1950-1954 (Box 5, Folder 111)
      See also: box 11, folder 267
    - Hill, Lister, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Hilleboe, Herman E., 1948-1951, 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Hilles, Charles D., Jr., 1949-1958, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Hiscock, Ira Vaughn, 1957-1962 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Hospital Council of Philadelphia, 1956-1960 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Houghton, Walter, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Hudson Chamber of Commerce, 1950-1951, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Hudson Junior Chamber of Commerce, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Hudson High School Forum, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Hudson River Conservation Society, Inc., 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Hudson River Regional Mental Health Planning Committee, 1963-1964January-June (Box 5, Folder 120-122)
    - I (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Industries for Columbia County, Inc., 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Ingraham, Hollis (Box 5, Folder 124)
      See: box 48, folder 384
    - International Ladies Garment Workers' Union, 1958-1964 (Box 5, Folder 125)
      See also: box 13, folder 309
    - J (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Jacobson, George W. (Box 5, Folder 126)
      See: box 53, folder 43
    - Johnson, Robert L., 1958-1964 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Judd, Allyn F., 1956-1961, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - K (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Kaiser Foundation (Box 6, Folder 129)
      See: box 19, folder 455
    - Keene, Clifford (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Kerr, Lorin E., 1958-1964 (Box 6, Folder 130)
      See also: box 11, folder 261
      See also: box 50, folders 1-34
      See also: box 59, folder 99
      See also: box 6, folder 157
    - Kingren, Gibson (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Kiphuth, Robert J. H., 1947-1951 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Kirkland, Lane, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Klem, Margaret C., 1955-1961 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Kornfeld, Allan (Box 6, Folder 133)
      See: box 12, folder 282
    - Kubie, Lawrence S., 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - L (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Larimore, Granville W., 1951, 1957, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 136)
      See also: box 81, folder 306
    - Larkin, Vincent DePaul (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Lawrence, David, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Lear, Walter J., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Leavitt, Kent, 1948-1959 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Lee, Russell V., 1953-1964 (Box 6, Folder 140)
      See also: box 1, folders 8, 9
    - Levin, Fay A., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Levin, Morton L., 1948-1951 (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Lipton, Martin (Box 6, Folder 142)
      See: box 42, folder 313
    - Littauer, David, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Locke, John, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - M (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - MacColl, William A., 1956, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - McCormack, James (Box 6, Folder 146)
      See: box 16, folders 393-398
    - McCree, Wade H. (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - McGuinness, Aims C., 1959, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 147)
      See also: box 16, folder 397
    - MacLeod, Gordon K. (Box 6, Folder 147)
      See: box 48, folders 385-403
    - Mattison, Berwyn (Box 6, Folder 147)
      See: box 50, folders 1-34
    - Mayer, Vera (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Medical Administrators Conference, 1957-1960 (Box 6, Folder 148-149)
    - Medical Economics, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Medical Foundation of Bellaire (Box 6, Folder 150)
      See: box 64, folders 162-163
      See: box 3, folder 53
    - Medical Society of the State of New York (Box 6, Folder 150)
      See: box 7, folder 167
    - Medicare (Box 6, Folder 150)
      See: box 64, folder 156
      See: box 59, folder 107
    - Melamed, Isidor, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Meltzer, Marcin (Box 6, Folder 151)
      See: box 47, folder 368
      See: box 10, folder 249-258
    - Metcalf, George R., 1958-1963 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Moore, Norman S., 1955-1963 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Mott, Frederick D., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 154)
      See also: box 60, folder 110
      See also: box 40, folder 289
    - Mudge, Stern, Baldwin and Todd, 1952-1959 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Myers, Glynn (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - N (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - National Council of Senior Citizens, Inc. (Box 6, Folder 156)
      See: box 13, folder 306
    - National Health Council, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - National Institutes on Rehabilitation and Health Services, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - National Rehabilitation Association, 1959-1964 (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Nelson, John A. (Box 6, Folder 158)
      See: box 58, folder 95
    - New York Academy of Medicine, 1957-1961 (Box 6, Folder 159)
      See also: box 42, folders 311-374
    - New York Academy of Medicine, Committee on Special Studies, Subcommittee on Social Policy for Health Care, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - New York Hotel Trades Council and Hotel Association of New York City Health Center, Inc., 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - New York State Citizens' Council, 1956-1961, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - New York State Council on Youth, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - New York State Department of Health, 1948-1951, 1957-1958, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 165)
      See also: box 6, folder 136
      See also: box 5, folder 112
    - New York State Department of Health, Junior Public Health Intern Program, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - New York State Interdepartmental Health Resources Board (Box 7, Folder 166)
      See: box 3, folder 45
    - New York State Joint Hospital Survey and Planning Commission, Albany Regional Hospital Planning Council (Box 7, Folder 166)
      See: box 7, folder 185
    - New York State Medical Society, 1955-1963 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - New York State Office for the Aging, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - New York State Public Health Association, 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Northern Dutchess Health Center, 1955-1964 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Notkin, Herbert, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - O (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Office Employees International Union, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - O'Hearn, Charles M., 1950-1959 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - O'Meara, Edward S., 1957-1960 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Osborn, Stanley H., 1955 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Oughterson, A.W., 1948-1950 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - P (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Palo Alto Clinic (Box 7, Folder 175)
      See: box 6, folder 141
    - Parkhurst, Leonard, 1949-1951 (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Physicians Forum, Inc., 1959-1964 (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - Pillsbury, Philip, 1954-1960 (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - Pomeroy, Robert Watson, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Pond, M. Allen, 1957-1963 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Prentice, J. Rockefeller, 1953-1963 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Prentice, P.I., 1964 (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Preston, Jerome, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - R (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Regional Hospital Review and Planning Council of Northeastern New York, Inc., 1955-1960 (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - Regional Hospital Review and Planning Council of Northeastern New York, Inc., 1961-1963 January-Aug, 1963 October-Dec, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 186-190)
    - Rehabilitation Codes, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Reuther, Walter P. (Box 8, Folder 191)
      See: box 40, Folder 282
    - Ribicoff, Abraham (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Robertson, Alexander (Box 8, Folder 191)
      See: box 16, folder 383
    - Robertson (Gilbert A.) Home, 1947-1956 (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - Roemer, Milton, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 193)
      See also: box 51, folder 21
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Roosevelt (Eleanor) Memorial Foundation, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Rorem, C. Rufus, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Rose, Milton C., 1950 (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - Rosenthal, Paul, 1948-1954 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Russell, Theodore B., 1948-1959 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Ryan, Allan A., 1953-1962 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Sa - Sm (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Sn - Su (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - St. John, Fordyce Barker, 1948-1950 (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - Sawyer, William A., 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - Segadelli, Louis (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - Seidman, Bert (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - Seton Hall College of Medicine and Dentistry, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - Seubold, Frank (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - Sheps, Cecil G. (Box 9, Folder 205)
      See also: box 43, folder 316
    - Shoemaker, Richard (Box 9, Folder 205)
      See: box 80, folder 294
    - Shortlifte, Ernest C. (Box 9, Folder 205)
      See: box 64, folder 161
    - Siebert, Jane (Box 9, Folder 205)
    - Silver, George A., 1959-1962 (Box 9, Folder 206)
      See also: box 18, folder 451
    - Snoke, Albert W., 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 207)
    - Snoke, Parnie S., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 207)
    - Somers, Herman (Box 9, Folder 207)
      See: box 15, folder 373
    - Spock, Benjamin, 1948, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 208)
    - Stark, Nathan (Box 9, Folder 208)
      See: box 47, folder 369
    - Stewart, William H., 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 209)
    - Stout, Arthur Purdy, 1946-1951 (Box 9, Folder 210)
    - Straus, Donald B., 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 211)
      See also: box 10, folder 243
      See also: box 78, folders 267-305
    - Studer, Augustus C., Jr., 1949-1956 (Box 9, Folder 212)
    - Studer, Margot (Mrs. Augustus C.), 1955-1963 (Box 9, Folder 213)
    - T (Box 9, Folder 214)
    - Talbot, John H., 1959 (Box 9, Folder 215)
    - Terris, Milton, 1955-1958, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 216)
      See also: box 20, folder 476
    - Time, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 217)
    - Travell, Janet, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 218)
    - Trese, John A. (Box 9, Folder 218)
      See: box 42, folder 304
    - Triest, Carl G., 1947-1960 (Box 9, Folder 219)
    - Trussell, Ray E., 1950-1964 (Box 9, Folder 220)
    - U (Box 9, Folder 221)
    - United Auto Workers (Box 9, Folder 221)
      See: box 3, folder 46
    - United Mine Workers of America (Box 9, Folder 221)
      See: box 6, folder 130
      See: box 13, folder 309
      See: box 13, folder 315
      See: box 14, folder 352
    - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare (Box 9, Folder 221)
      See: box 3, folder 61
      See: box 7, folder 180
      See: box 9, folder 209
      See: box 9, folder 231
      See: box 12, folder 275-277
      See: box 12, folder 297
      See: box 13, folder 336-337
      See: box 16, folder 386